Frank Ormsby papers, circa 1967-2004
Emory University
- Printed material, circa 1965-1991, Series 5; Box 30: folders 9-72 - Box 34; OP 6, 10-19
  - Printed material by Frank Ormsby, Subseries 5.1; Box 30: folders 9-72; OP 6, 10
    - "The Lady Next Door," in The Irish Press, 12 August 1972 (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - "Last Night," in The Irish Press, 29 April 1978 (Box OP10)
    - "Losing a Day," in The Irish Press, 16 April 1977 (Box OP10)
    - "M. On Night Duty," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - "Manifesto," in The Honest Ulsterman, January - February 1973 (Box 30, Folder 38)
    - "McQuade," [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Defense of Posie"]
    - "Mechanics" and "Woodland Near a Manor," in The Connacht Tribune, 1 May 1981 (Box 30, Folder 39)
    - "Moving In," translation into Romanian (1981) (Box 30, Folder 40)
    - "Mrs. G Watters," in The Irish Press, 12 August 1972 (Box 30, Folder 41)
    - "My Careful Life," in New Statesman, 12 August 1983 (Box 30, Folder 42)
    - "On Devenish Island," [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Island Honeymoon"]
    - "One Saturday," in unknown source [also includes "Happy Anniversary," MS] [photocopy] (Box 30, Folder 43)
    - "A. N. Other," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 44)
    - "A Paris Honeymoon: L'Orangerie," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 45)
    - "Passing the Crematorium," in The Irish Press, 16 April 1977 (Box OP10)
    - "Patrick," in unknown source [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "For Matthew"]
    - "Premarital rite, Castle Junction," in unknown source [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Dustmen"]
    - "Relief Map," in unknown number of The Honest Ulsterman (Box 30, Folder 46)
    - "Sarajevo," in unknown source [photocopy] (Box 30, Folder 47)
    - "Skyhooks," [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Bundoran"]
    - "Territories," in unknown source [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "A Belfast Journal II"]
    - "To a Favorite Cow," [juvenilia] [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Compromise]
    - "Under the Stairs," in unknown source [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Inferno: A New Circle"]
    - "Used Cars," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 48)
    - "Virgins," in Irish Times, 30 May 1970 (Box 30, Folder 49)
    - "Waiting for a Connection," in The Irish Press, 16 April 1977 (Box OP10)
    - "Walkers Observed," in Gown, 6 May 1976 (Box OP10)
    - "Walking Home at Night," in The Irish Press, 16 April 1977 (Box OP10)
    - "Waste Ground Near a Bridge," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 50)
    - "Water," in TLS, 21 may 1982 (Box 30, Folder 51)
    - "Winter Offerings," translation into Romanian (1981) [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Moving In"]
    - Prose
    - "Balancing the Book," Essay on Poets from the North of Ireland in Poetry Book Society Bulletin, spring 1991 (Box 30, Folder 52)
    - "The Daddy of Us All," review of The Selected John Hewitt in the Belfast Telegraph, 2 October 1981 (Box 30, Folder 53)
    - "Diary of a Trip to Saskatoon," essay in Fortnight, May 1987 (Box 30, Folder 54)
    - "Frank Ormsby writes…," essay in The Poetry Book Society Bulletin, Christmas 1977 (Box 30, Folder 55)
    - "From Celtic to Barbwire Twilight," review of Padraic Fiacc's The Selected Padraic Fiacc, in Belfast Telegraph, 22 September 1979 (Box 30, Folder 56)
    - "Grammatical Grandeur," [juvenilia] [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Compromise]
    - "Heaney: Promise of Better Things to Come," review of Field Work in Belfast Telegraph, 9 November 1979 (Box 30, Folder 57)
    - "Heaney's ‘Voices' Raine's ‘Riches,'" review of Heaney's Station Island and Raine's Rich, in unknown, undated newspaper [See also Subseries 3.2: Prose by Ormsby (essays), "Heaney's ‘Voices,' Raine's ‘Riches'"] (Box 30, Folder 58)
    - "John Hewitt's ‘Chosen Ground,'" review of John Hewitt's The Day of the Corncrake: Poems of the Nine Glens, in unknown, undated newspaper [See also Subseries 3.2: Prose by Ormsby (essays), "John Hewitt's ‘Chosen Ground'"] (Box 30, Folder 59)
    - "A Journey Back," review of Roy McFadden's After Seymour's Funeral, in Belfast Telegraph, 12 October 1990 [See also Subseries 2.2: The Honest Ulsterman author files, McFadden] (Box 30, Folder 60)
    - "Local Promptings," essay in The Poetry Book Society Bulletin, 1986 [See also Subseries 3.2: Prose by Ormsby (essays) "Local Promptings"] (Box 30, Folder 61)
    - "The Long Embrace," article about The Long Embrace in BBC Northern Ireland's Radio Times, 19 February 1988 [See also Subseries 3.4: Works edited by Ormsby, The Long Embrace] (Box 30, Folder 62)
    - "Longley: Chapter and Verse," review of Longley's Poems 1963-1983, in Belfast Telegraph, 26 March 1985 [See also Subseries 3.2: Prose by Ormsby (essays), "Longley: Chapter and Verse"] (Box 30, Folder 63)
    - "On the Wild Side," review of Robert Johnston's All Shy Wildness, in unknown, undated newspaper (Box 30, Folder 64)
    - "Personal Gestures," review of Kinsella's The New Oxford Book of Irish Verse and Muldoon's The Faber Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry, in The Times Educational Supplement, 11 July 1986 [See also Subseries 3.2: Prose by Ormsby (essays), "Personal Gestures"] (Box OP6)
    - "Philadelphia, Here I Come," essay in Abbey Theatre program for 1972 production of Philadelphia, Here I Come by Brian Friel (Box 30, Folder 65)
    - "Poetic Novel," review of Juanita Casey's The Horse of Seline, in Irish Press, 29 May 1971 (Box 30, Folder 66)
    - "The Poetry of an Ulster Life," review of Robert Johnstone's Eden to Edenderry, in Belfast Telegraph, 11 September 1989 (Box 30, Folder 67)
    - "Poets Enhance Series Reputation," review of Elliott's, McAuley's and O'Driscoll's Trio 4, in Belfast Telegraph, 8 July 1985 (Box 30, Folder 68)
    - "Searching for Home," review of Norman Dugdale's Corncrake in Belfast Telegraph, 8 August 1978 (Box 30, Folder 69)
    - "Showcase for Writers of All Kinds," in unknown, undated newspaper (Box 30, Folder 70)
    - "Survival Fables," review of Joszef Lengyel's Acta Sanctorum in Irish Press, 7 October 1970 (Box 30, Folder 71)
    - "Ulster Poet Waxing Lyrical on Debut," review of Peter McDonald's Biting the Wax, in Belfast Telegraph, 18 June 1990 (Box 30, Folder 72)
    - "Unlikely Conversation Between Butcher and Housewife," in Arís, St. Michael's College Magazine 1966 (Box 30, Folder 73)
    - Miscellaneous poems 1970-1978 [See Subseries 5.2: Printed material about Ormsby, Scrapbook 1970-1978]
  - Printed material about Frank Ormsby, Subseries 5.2; Box 31 - Box 32: folders 1-19; OP 11-13
    This subseries organizes printed material about Ormsby in four separate subsections. The first subsection includes articles, essays, and biographical sketches about Ormsby as a poet and editor. The second subsection groups together numerous notices and reviews of Ormsby's poetry up to A Northern Spring (1986). These texts are arranged by the volume of poetry they consider. The next subsection collects the notices and reviews of the various books Ormsby has edited. A fourth subsection contains materials relevant to the promotion of Ormsby's poetry volumes and other books. This subsection includes many announcements and programs from Ormsby's own poetry readings, giving a sense his public literary life.
    - Articles and Essays about Ormsby
    - Awards and honors for Ormsby (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Fiacc, Padraic: "The North's Younger Poets," in Hibernia, 20 October 1972 [also addresses Derek Mahon, Paul Muldoon, and Michael Boyle (Box OP11)
    - Artists Writers in Schools Directory, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Anonymous, biographical blurb for International Authors and Writers Who's Who, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Anonymous, "Traveling Bards," [translated from Romanian] in Panoramic Britanic, circa October 1987 [See also Subseries 5.2: Printed material about Ormsby, promotional materials and readings, Romania] (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook 1970-1978 [includes poems, reviews, and essays by Ormsby as well as reviews and clippings about Ormsby or The Honest Ulsterman] (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Reviews and Clippings about Ormsby's Poetry
    - Reviews and Clippings of Business as Usual (1973) [See also Subseries 5.2: Printed material about Ormsby, articles and essays, scrapbook 1970-1978] (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Reviews and Clippings of A Store of Candles (1977) [See also Subseries 5.2: Printed material about Ormsby, articles and essays, scrapbook 1970-1978] (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Reviews and Clippings of Being Walked by a Dog (1978) (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Reviews and Clippings of A Northern Spring (1986) (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Reviews and Clippings of A Northern Spring (1986) [scrapbook] (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Reviews and Clippings about Ormsby's Edited Volumes
    - Reviews and Clippings of Poets from the North of Ireland (first edition, 1979) (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Reviews and Clippings of Poets from the North of Ireland (1979) (Box OP12)
    - Reviews and Clippings of Poets from the North of Ireland (second edition, 1991) (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Reviews and Clippings of Northern Windows: An Anthology of Ulster Autobiography (1987) (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Reviews and Clippings of Northern Windows: An Anthology of Ulster Autobiography (1987) [scrapbook] (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Reviews and Clippings of Thine in Storm and Calm: An Amanda McKittrick Ros Reader (1988) (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Reviews and Clippings of The Long Embrace: Twentieth Century Irish Love Poems (1990) (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Reviews and Clippings of The Long Embrace: Twentieth Century Irish Love Poems (1990) [publication announcements] (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Reviews and Clippings of The Long Embrace: Twentieth Century Irish Love Poems (1990) [scrapbook] (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Reviews and Clippings of The Collected Poems of John Hewitt (1991) (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Reviews and Clippings of The Collected Poems of John Hewitt (1991) [scrapbook] (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Reviews and Clippings of A Rage for Order (1992) (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Reviews and Clippings of A Rage for Order (1992) [scrapbook] (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous Articles about Frank Ormsby (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Promotional Materials and Readings
    - Queens University Festival, 9-20 February 1972, reading with Foley, Muldoon, Peskett (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Festival of Ulster Poetry at the Institute for Contemporary Arts, London, 17-21 February 1976 [readers include: Ormsby, Heaney, Hewitt, Longley, Montague, Muldoon, Paulin, Peskett, Simmons] (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Irvinestown Arts Festival, 18 February 1977, with readings by Ormsby, Simmons, Muldoon (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Irvinestown Arts Festival, 18 February 1977, with readings by Ormsby, Simmons, Muldoon (Box OP13)
    - Queens University Belfast, 29 November 1977, with readings by Ormsby, Mahon] (Box OP13)
    - Queens University Belfast Anglo-Irish Conference on Poets from the North of Ireland, 20-21 March 1980 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - University of Saskatchewan, Canadian Association for Irish Studies Conference, 18-21 February 1987 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Romania, reading tour with Fleur Adcock, sponsored by The British Council, 2-10 October 1987 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Newcastle Poetry Festival, 17 September 1988 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - The Second John Hewitt Summer School, 31 July - 7 August 1989 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Queens University Belfast opening for Poets from the North of Ireland by Frank Ormsby, ed. (1991); with readings by Ormsby, Carson, Dawe, Greacen, Hughes, Johnstone, Simmons (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Dukes Hotel, Belfast, 1994, with readings by Ormsby and James Simmons (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Germany, reading tour with James Simmons, sponsored by The British Council, 29 January - 5 February 1994 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - The Belfast Institute reading, 7 December 1994 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Aspects: A Celebration of Irish Writing, Bangor, 29 September 1995 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - William Carleton Summer School, 7-11 August 1995 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Northern Ireland Cultural Program with Europe: Saxony-Anhalt Teachers Study Tour, 1-8 October 1995 [reading with McGuckian] (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Tallinn, Estonia: Irish Cultural Week 28 October - 4 November 1995 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Cultural Diversity in Contemporary Europe: An International Conference, 23-28 June 1996 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Ulster Museum, 30 June 1996, with readings by Ormsby and Watson (Box OP13)
    - Belfast Festival at Queens, 4-23 November 1996 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Undated Ormsby readings (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Other printed material, Subseries 5.3; Box 32: folders 20-74 - Box 34: folders 1-6; OP 11, 13-19
    The subseries for other printed material contains a wide assortment of texts grouped by type. The most prominent subsection is that dedicated to printed material by others. Ormsby has collected a large number of published poems, stories, reviews, and essays by an assortment of mostly Irish writers. These documents are arranged in alphabetical order by author. In some cases, Ormsby amassed multiple reviews of specific texts. These have been gathered together and listed as "assorted reviews" of a particular text. Furthermore, a number of folders contain miscellaneous, sometimes unattributed articles grouped together according to specific subjects or themes. Another subsection consists of various whole journals or magazines retained because of the literary or cultural relevance of particular articles. The printed material subseries also holds a substantial collection of theater and other event programs. The numerous playbills relating to specific theaters have been arranged according to theater. These offer a snapshot of the Dublin and Belfast theater scenes in the 1970's and 1980's. Other event programs are arranged in a more heterogeneous subsection.
    Arranged in alphabetical order.
    - Printed Material by Others
    - Anonymous, untitled review of The Honest Ulsterman, No. 50 in The Irish Times, [1976] (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Anonymous, "Comedy the Only Poetry: Lecture on Kavanagh," [article on Brendan Kennelly's radio lecture on Kavanagh] in The Irish Times, 18 May 1971 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Anonymous, "The Honest Ulsterman," [review] of The Honest Ulsterman, No. 50 in Notes and Queries, No. 67 [1976] (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Boland, Eavan, "Poets and Chorus," [reviews of Paul Durcan's Sam's Crossing, John Hewitt's's The Rain Dance, and The Honest Ulsterman] in The Irish Times, 23 December 1978 (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Brandes, Rand, "From Soundings to Sound Bites," [review of Michael Parker's Seamus Heaney: The Making of a Poet] in The Irish Literary Supplement, fall 1993 (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Bredin, Hugh, "The Lonely Road to Fivemiletown [review of Tom Paulin's Fivemiletown (1987)] in The Irish News, 31 December 1987 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Carson, Ciaran, "Belfast Notes," in TLS 24-30 June 1988 (Box OP14)
    - Carson, Ciaran, "Gag," [poem] in Ulster News Letter, 7 January, 1991 (Box OP15)
    - Carson, Ciaran, "Saw," [poem] in Ulster News Letter, 7 January, 1991 (Box OP15)
    - Carty, Ciaran, "Benedict Kiely: Creative writing is all lies!" [review of Benedict Kiely] in Sunday Independent, 22 February 1981 (Box OP11)
    - Clarke, Austin, "Poets of the Rising" in The Irish Press, 16 April 1966 (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - Collins, William, "The Aghadowey Oosteruck," and "Life—A Literary Curiosity," [essays] in The Chronicle, Ballymena, 23 September 1972 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - Cook, Jon, "New Found Land," [review of Medbh McGuckian's Venus and the Rain] in the New Statesman, 31 August 1984 (Box 32, Folder 28)
    - Dawe, Gerald, "Checkpoints: the Younger Irish Poets," [review of H.U.] in unknown source (Box 32, Folder 29)
    - Deane, John F., "Sequences" [review of Ciaran Carson's The Lost Explorer and Tom Paulin's Personal Column] in unknown source (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - Dickson, E. Jane, "Bards of Belfast," in unknown magazine (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Dugan, Matt, assorted poems [includes: "Words," "Morning," "Little Streams," "The Pritta," "The Lights of Lisnaskay," "The Candidates," "A Summer Day," "October '72," "The Weather," "St. Patrick's Day '73," "Life or Death," "The Welcome," "Euphoria," "Reflections," "The Snow"] (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - Dunne, Sean, "Singing to the Stones," [review of Richard Murphy's The Price of Stone] in unknown source (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - Galbraith, Georgia Starbuck, "Teen-Age Tragedy," [poem] in Saturday Evening Post, 3 January 1951 [photocopy] (Box 32, Folder 34)
    - Greacen, Robert, "The Rainbow Tree," signed greetings (Box 32, Folder 35)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "You Know When It Sounds Right," in the Belfast Telegraph, 20 November 1968 (Box 32, Folder 36)
    - Hofmann, Michael, "The Recent Generations at Their Song" [review of Dillon Johnston, Paul Muldoon, Thomas Kinsella, Derek Mahon, Edna Longley, Paul Durcan] in TLS 30 May 1986 (Box 32, Folder 37)
    - Hull, Gerry, "Slieve Beagh" (Box 32, Folder 38)
    - Jenkins, Alan, "More Than Just a Touch of the Irish," [review of Paul Muldoon's The Faber Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry] in unknown source, circa 1986-1987 (Box 32, Folder 39)
    - Jordan, John, "Magazine Scene," [essay] in The Irish Press, 6 April 1978 (Box 32, Folder 40)
    - Kavanagh, Patrick, "The Book of Film," [review] in The Standard, 18 April 1947 (Box 32, Folder 41)
    - Kavanagh, Patrick, "Patrick Kavanagh is Sentimental Over Fairs," [essay] in Irish Farmers' Journal, 7 February 1959 (Box 32, Folder 42)
    - Kavanagh, Patrick, "A Wonderful Time," [essay] in Irish Farmers' Journal, 4 July 1959 (Box 32, Folder 43)
    - Kiberd, Declan, "Non-Protesting Protestants" [review of Gerald Dawe's and Edna Longley's Across a Roaring Hill; Seamus Deane's Celtic Revivals] in unknown source (Box 32, Folder 44)
    - Kiely, Benedict, "Poetess of the Strawberry Beds," [review of Raymond Brooke's autobiography] in The Irish Times, 9 December 1967(?) (Box 32, Folder 45)
    - Longley, Edna, "Poetry from the North," [essay] in unknown newspaper [circa 1976] (Box 32, Folder 46)
    - Longley, Michael, "My Life… Alf McCreary Talks to Michael Longley" in Ulster Tatler, Christmas 1985 (Box 32, Folder 47)
    - Lowry, Suzanne, "Poetry: Who Reads It?" [profiles of local poets including Hewitt, Montague, Rodgers, Mahon, Simmons, Longley, Heaney] in Belfast Telegraph, 21 November 1968 (Box 32, Folder 48)
    - MacInerney, John, "Recent Poetry," by [review of Kinsella's Finistere] in The Irish Press, 23 December 1972 (Box 32, Folder 49)
    - MacRèamoinn, Sean, "Genesis of Genius" [remembrance of Kavanagh] in unknown source, July 1979 (Box 32, Folder 50)
    - Mahon, Derek, "Death and the Sun," [poem] in TLS, 26 July 1985 [See also series 5.4, O'Donoghue's "Adhering to Detachment"] (Box 32, Folder 51)
    - Mahon, Derek, "A Garage in Co. Cork," [poem] in TLS, 14 May 1982 (Box OP15)
    - Mahon, Derek, "The Sheep and Goats," [review of Muldoon's Faber Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry] in unknown source, 7 June 1986 (Box 32, Folder 52)
    - Mahood, G. A., "The Trout," in The Irish Press, 13 January 1983 (Box OP11)
    - Meir, Colin, "Poets from the North of Ireland," [lecture on 24 November 1985] reprinted in Regards Sur La Celtitude Contempraine (Box 32, Folder 53)
    - Meir, Colin, "Twentieth-Century Anglo-Irish Epic" (Box 32, Folder 54)
    - Montague, Evelyn, "Raver Reviewed," [Evelyn Montague writes about husband John Montague] in Inside Tribune, 14 April 1985 (Box 32, Folder 55)
    - O'Brien, Conor Cruise, "Micks and Prods," [review of Kinsella's The New Oxford Book of Irish Verse and Muldoon's Faber Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry] in unknown source (Box 32, Folder 56)
    - O'Brien, Darcy, "The California Life and Death of W. R. Rogers - 1," in The Irish Times, 11 March 1970 (Box 32, Folder 57)
    - O'Connor, John, "Neilly and the Fir Tree," TS [BBC radio script produced by Paul Muldoon, transmitted 30 January 1976] (Box 32, Folder 58)
    - O'Connor, John, "The Rock," TS [BBC radio script read by John Hewitt, transmitted 23 January 1977] (Box 32, Folder 59)
    - O'Donoghue, Bernard, "Adhering to Detachment," [review of Michael Longley's Poems: 1963-1983] in TLS, 26 July 1985 [photocopy] [See also series 5.3, Other printed material, Mahon's "Death and the Sun"] (Box 32, Folder 60)
    - O'Toole, Fintan, "Go and Read Derek Mahon," [essay] in The Irish Times, 2 February 1991 (Box 32, Folder 61)
    - Rogers, W. R., "Armagh Through Fifteen Centuries," [essay] in R.T., 4 January 1957 (Box 32, Folder 62)
    - Rogers, W. R., "Facets of Yeats," [review of The Letters of W.B. Yeats] in The Observer, 6 February 1955 (Box 32, Folder 63)
    - Rogers, W. R., "Home Thoughts from Abroad," [poem] in Irish Times, 9 July 1966 (Box 32, Folder 64)
    - Rogers, W. R., "Resurrection," [includes text and score for "Have Him Not" and "We Will Always Beg theQuestion"] performed at Campion College, 1 April 1988 (Box 32, Folder 65)
    - Rogers, W. R., "The Train," [poem] in New Statesman, 28 February 1948 (Box 32, Folder 66)
    - Shaw, Bob, "Poetry: Who Reads It?" in Belfast Telegraph, 22 November 1968 (Box 32, Folder 67)
    - Silverlight, John, "Brooding Images," [essay: profile of Seamus Heaney] in The Observer, 11 November 1979 [photocopy] (Box 32, Folder 68)
    - Waterman, Andrew "Ulsterectomy," [essay] in PN Review, vol. 3 [1975] (Box 32, Folder 69)
    - Assorted reviews of Thomas Kinsella's The New Oxford Book of Irish Verse (1986) [includes articles by: Peter Sirr, Terence Killeen, Joseph O'Neill] (Box 32, Folder 70)
    - Assorted reviews of Tom Paulin's Ireland and the English Crisis (1984) [includes articles by: Fintan O'Toole, Barry White, Enoch Powell, and Mary Holland] (Box 32, Folder 71)
    - Assorted reviews of Tom Paulin's The Faber Book of Political Verse (1986) [includes articles by: George Steiner, Dick Davis] (Box 32, Folder 72)
    - Miscellaneous reviews and writings by others, 1959-1991 (Box OP16)
    - Miscellaneous articles about literature (Box 32, Folder 73)
    - Miscellaneous articles about art (Box 32, Folder 74)
    - Miscellaneous biographies and interviews [subjects include: William Allingham, Joseph Campbell, Paul Durcan, David Herbison, Jennifer Johnstone, Michael Longley, Robert Lynd, Roy McFadden, Sean O'Faolain, Tom Paulin, James Simmons, Joe Tomelty, W. B. Yeats] (Box OP17)
    - Miscellaneous articles about the Northern Irish Troubles (Box OP18)
    - Journals, Magazines, Newspapers
    - The Annaghmakerrig Gazebo, Nos. 1-2 [October 1983; October 1984] (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Belfast Jewish Record, June 1973 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Gown, 28 April 1977 [includes: John Hewitt's "In the Lenin Library, Dushanbe," Michael Longley's "Mythology," Paul Muldoon's "Palm Sunday," and Tom Paulin's "Faces"] (Box OP11)
    - The National Trust Magazine, summer 1991 [includes article on The Crown Saloon, Belfast] (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Theater Programs
    - The Belfast Arts Theatre (1971, 1980, 1981, 1984) [includes: Brendan Behan's The Hostage, Brian Friel's Philadelphia, Here I Come!] (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - The Field Day Theatre Company (1984) [Tom Paulin's The Riot Act, Derek Mahon's High Time] (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Grand Opera House, Belfast (1970, 1980) [includes: Ulster Drama Festival, George Bernard Shaw's John Bull's Other Island] (Box 33, Folder 6)